<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English on niklas-stephan.de</title><link>https://niklas-stephan.de/tags/english/</link><description>Recent content in English on niklas-stephan.de</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>de</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://niklas-stephan.de/tags/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup your own ChatGPT clone in 5 minutes</title><link>https://niklas-stephan.de/blog/chatgpt-clone/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://niklas-stephan.de/blog/chatgpt-clone/</guid><description>&lt;p>And another post about A.I… And why this headline? &lt;a href="https://chat.openai.com/" target="_blank">OpenAI’s ChatGPT&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://copilot.microsoft.com/" target="_blank">Microsoft’s Co-Pilot&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.salesforce.com/news/press-releases/2023/03/07/einstein-generative-ai/" target="_blank">Salesforce’s Einstein&lt;/a> are just running well! But,
are they? And even if you are happy about them, are you willing to pay regular
(not cheap) license fees for all of your employees, even if they just use it
from time to time? Also, do you really trust Big Tech’s promises about confidentiallity,
when it’s about your intellectual property? If you answer all of this by yes,
you can stop reading, now.
But, in case you would like to know how you easily can run your own A.I. chatbot
or you are just curious like me, about how that is done, my article gives you an
overview how to do that by utilizing the two amazing tools &lt;a href="https://ollama.com/" target="_blank">Ollama&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://openwebui.com/" target="_blank">Open WebUI&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My website charged with Aritificial Intelligence</title><link>https://niklas-stephan.de/blog/ai-on-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://niklas-stephan.de/blog/ai-on-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>After years of tinkering with various CMS systems and even creating one of my own,
one thing remains constant: the struggle to craft captivating content! ⏳ But fear not,
because I’m tapping into the newest technology – AI! ?
Check out my latest post on how artificial intelligence maybe can revolutionize content creation,
translations, and even programming. Dive into the cutting-edge with me at &lt;a href="https://niklas-stephan.de" target="_blank">niklas-stephan.de &lt;/a>!
#AI #ContentCreation #Innovation“&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="user-experience">User Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="02_niklas-stephan.deBrandbyDesigner.png" alt="Brand Proposal">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Passwordless SSH Login to a Remote Server with Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://niklas-stephan.de/blog/ssh-copy-id/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://niklas-stephan.de/blog/ssh-copy-id/</guid><description>&lt;p>Following article describes how to enable You to login to a Remote Server with the industry standard
SSH network protocol by using a key and Visual Studio Code, so you do not have to enter your user/password every
time you want to connect. It was written for/on MacOS, but the procedure should be the same on Linux and similar for Windows.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="preparation">Preparation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At first &lt;a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/" target="_blank">download&lt;/a>, install and open VS Code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="02_grafik.png" alt="Remote SSH">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learn Next.js - Chapter 18: Docker Environment</title><link>https://niklas-stephan.de/blog/next-js-18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://niklas-stephan.de/blog/next-js-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you went successfully through Vercel&amp;rsquo;s free and amazing &lt;a href="https://nextjs.org/learn/dashboard-app" target="_blank">Learn Next.js&lt;/a> online course,
you have end up in a nice and &amp;ldquo;fast&amp;rdquo; (the database access is actually slow,
but that was on purpose for better understanding of the tutorial) Demo of a
modern web application. You have also learned about plenty considerations
when developing an web app. So now, you maybe feel like &amp;ldquo;How can I use all of this
for a real project?&amp;rdquo;. Also there are still some constraints left like;
&amp;ldquo;How can I get independent from Vercel&amp;rsquo;s nice but (in their free plan) slow hosting offer?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>